(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
こんこよアイランドへようこそ！
博衣こより生誕Live 2024
勝手にDay 0!?
Welcome to Kon-koyo Island!
Hakui Koyori Birthday Live 2024
Day 0 on my own!?
こんこよ！こゆびだよ！
Kon-koyo! It's Koyubi!
せーの！こんこよーべーす！
One-two! Kon-koyo-base!
はい！ハッシュタグ！こより実験中でした！
Yes! Hashtag! Koyori was in the middle of an experiment!
オーケー！こよは！ズボマ！
Okay! Koyo is... Zuboma!
ズボマですか？はい！やったー！
Are you Zuboma? Yes! Yay!
こよりスケッチ！デデーン！はい！はい！せーの！
Koyori Sketch! Dede-n! Yes! Yes! Ready, go!
天球社らしし変換！
Tenkyuusha-like conversion!
わー！命の変換！
Wow! Conversion of life!
こよりの助手はワンネーム！
Koyori's assistants are one-name!
ふあふあ！ヘルプ！
Fua-fua! Help!
うわー！ボンビーノ！
Uwaa! Bombino!
ズボマなんでね！ミーアカ！
Because I'm Zuboma! Mi-aka!
可愛いですね！いやー！
You're cute! No way!
オーケー！こんこよーべーす！
Okay! Kon-koyo-base!
わー！やったー！間に合った！
Wow! Yay! I made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！ちなみに私はクッキーです！
Mayonnaise is a drink! By the way, I'm a cookie!
はい！お兄ちゃん！変換！冷凍うどんは常備してます！
Yes! Big brother! Conversion! I always have frozen udon!
どうですか？はい！やったー！照明完了Q.E.D.！
How's that? Yes! Yay! Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
ゴクゴクゴクゴク！ぷはー！美味しいでした！
Gulp, gulp, gulp, gulp! Phew! That was delicious!
こよりには！しっぽもくるくる！
For Koyori! Even my tail goes round and round!
お召し上がりま！むいむいむいむい！
Enjoy your meal! Mui-mui-mui-mui!
ぷやー！いけませんね！
Puya! That's not good!
思い出し笑い！そー！
Remembering something funny and laughing! That's right!
ふわふわのプログラム！溶けそう！
A fluffy program! It's about to melt!
あー！お見事です！
Ah! Simply brilliant!
オーケー！いけ！こよー！せーの！
Okay! Go! Koyo! Ready, go!
うー！やったー！間に合った！
Ooh! Yay! I made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！ちなみに私はクッキーです！
Mayonnaise is a drink! By the way, I'm a cookie!
はい！お兄ちゃん！変換！冷凍うどんは常備してます！
Yes! Big brother! Conversion! I always have frozen udon!
どうですか？はい！やったー！私の戦闘力54万です！
How's that? Yes! Yay! My power level is 540,000!
こよは！助手は！はい！こよりの助手は助手くんだよ！
Koyo is... assistants are... Yes! Koyori's assistants are Joshu-kun!
かけっこまじ！チョコ好き！
A real race! I like chocolate!
はい！あー！百五十五！
Yes! Ah! 155!
ジャンプは乗り物ではありません！
Jumping is not a vehicle!
オーロラ電子です！
It's Aurora Electronics!
しっぽもクッキー食べました！
Even my tail ate a cookie!
みんなの応援が一番だよ！右に！
Everyone's support is the best! To the right!
やったー！間に合った！
Yay! I made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！ちなみに私はクッキーです！
Mayonnaise is a drink! By the way, I'm a cookie!
はい！お兄ちゃん！変換！冷凍うどんは常備してます！
Yes! Big brother! Conversion! I always have frozen udon!
どうですか？はい！やったー！せーの！ゴッホコヨ！
How's that? Yes! Yay! Ready, go! Gogh-Koyo!
こんこよ！こゆびだよ！
Kon-koyo! It's Koyubi!
せーの！こんこよーべーす！
One-two! Kon-koyo-base!
HAKUI KOYORI BIRTHDAY LIVE
GUEST 赤井はあと
GUEST Akai Haato
「さぁ、ホロライブアイランドへ向かうぞ！」
"Now, let's head to Hololive Island!"
「な、なんだ！？舵が切れないぞ！？！？うわあああ！」
"Wh-What?! The rudder won't move! Aaaaaah!"
航海をしていたキミたちが漂流したのは「こんこよアイランド」
You, who were on a voyage, drifted to "Konkoyo Island".
癖の強い原住民たちがいそうな雰囲気のするこの島に、
On this island, which feels like it might have some eccentric natives...
キミたちは勇ましくも足を踏み入れるのだった。
...you bravely set foot.
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Another day of ruckus and mayhem
がおー！
Gaoo!
高らかに笑い合えば 友達（フレンズ）
If we laugh loudly together, we're Friends (Friends)
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and things get messy, we're still close
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
There are beasts, but no outcasts
本当の愛はここにある
True love is right here
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Look, you hold hands too, for a big adventure
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, two, three
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Another day of ruckus and mayhem
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone is different, and that's why we're attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If we gently overlap our fingers against the sunset sky...
はじめまして
Nice to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
がおー！
Gaoo!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
If we look back, there's trouble everywhere
なんてこった てんやわんや 止まらない
Oh boy, it's a hullabaloo, and it won't stop
けものですもの 大目に見ててね
We're beasts, so please bear with us
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely
そう 君も飾らなくて大丈夫
That's right, you don't have to put on airs either
はいどーぞ
Here you go
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you Japari Park!
今日からは どうぞよろしくね
From today on, please take care of me
いつもいつでも 優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
Always and forever, a gentle smile was waiting for you
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
If we talk about all our dreams through the opened door...
どこまでも続いてく グレートジャーニー
The Great Journey will continue forever
東へ吠えろ
Howl to the east
西へ吠えろ
Howl to the west
世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Let the Safari Melody ring out across the world
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Another day of ruckus and mayhem
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone is different, and that's why we're attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If we gently overlap our fingers against the sunset sky...
はじめまして
Nice to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
がおー！
Gaoo!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
集まれ友達
Gather round, friends
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful departure
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
派手な歓迎を受けたキミたちは、戸惑いながらも森の奥へ。
Having received a flashy welcome, you head deeper into the forest, albeit a bit bewildered.
感じながらも森の奥へ。
While feeling [it], heading deep into the forest.
待ち受けていたのは、甘い香りと怪しい雰囲気の小屋？
What was waiting there was a cottage with a sweet scent and a suspicious atmosphere?
這い寄りますか？ せーの、うねり！
Shall we crawl? One, two, surge!
SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！
SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch!
誰だ？ 邪魔するな my my LOVE
Who is it? Don't interfere, my my LOVE
(這い寄りしものどもよ)
(Oh, you crawling ones)
誰だ？ 守り抜け my my LOVE
Who is it? Protect it to the end, my my LOVE
(馬が蹴りしものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones kicked by horses)
理性が千切れる瞬間
The moment reason snaps
限界みたいだよ
It seems to be the limit
理性がぶっ飛ぶ瞬間
The moment reason flies away
あなたは逃げられない (逃がさない)
You can't escape (I won't let you escape)
そうだ！ 邪魔するな bye bye LIFE
That's right! Don't interfere, bye bye LIFE
(忌みよろこぶものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones who rejoice in abominations)
そうだ！ 諦めろ bye bye LIFE
That's right! Give up, bye bye LIFE
(重いあやかしものどもよ)
(Oh, you heavy mysterious ones)
「あの子欲しいよ」「あげない」
"I want that girl" "I won't give her to you"
かごめかごめ宇宙式 (うしろの正面)
Kagome Kagome cosmic style (Right behind you)
「あの子ください」「無理矢理」
"Give me that girl" "By force"
奪いたいのが愛の本能さ
The instinct of love is to want to snatch away
待て待て 嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ
Wait, wait, no, no, no
恋は渾沌の隷也
Love is a slave to chaos
現れし私はだあれ？
Who am I that has appeared?
恋は渾沌の隷也
Love is a slave to chaos
選ばれし君の神ですよ
I am your chosen god
ラブをクラフト戦いながらね
While fighting for love-crafting
とか何とか言っても本当はこんなにこんなに大好き
Regardless of what I say, I really love you this much, this much
這い寄りますか？ せーの、うねり！
Shall we crawl? One, two, surge!
SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！
SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch!
誰だ誰だ誰だ？ 愛撫する our our HEART
Who, who, who is it? Caressing our our HEART
(隠しきれないものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones who can't hide it all)
誰だ誰だ誰だ？ 押し付けろ our our HEART
Who, who, who is it? Press it against us, our our HEART
(這い寄りたーいものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones who want to crawl)
満ちては欠ける 純愛
Waxing and waning pure love
略奪みたいだね
It's like a plunder, isn't it?
満ちては歪んだ 純愛
Waxing and distorted pure love
あなたを逃がさない (逃がさない)
I won't let you escape (I won't let you escape)
そうそうそうなんだ！ 蹂躙しろ come come HELL
That's right, that's how it is! Overrun us, come come HELL
(冒涜的だったものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones who were blasphemous)
そうそうそうなんだ！ むしゃぶるえ come come HELL
That's right, that's how it is! Tremble with excitement, come come HELL
(合致したーいものどもよ)
(Oh, you ones who want to match)
「あの子食べます」「だめです」
"I'll eat that girl" "You can't"
花いちもんめ宇宙編 (あぶくふくらした)
Hana-ichi monme cosmic edition (The bubbles expanded)
「あの子食べます」「もぐもぐ」
"I'll eat that girl" "*munch munch*"
酸いも甘いも愛のバリエさ
Both sour and sweet are variations of love
すぐすぐ 来てきて来てきて
Right now, right now, come, come, come
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The strange future Nyarlathotep
困らせて幸せになれ
Trouble them and become happy
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The strange future Nyarlathotep
愛すべき君の神ですよ
I am your lovable god
宇宙的ホラーは見逃せないでしょう
You can't miss the cosmic horror, can you?
とか何とか言っても本当にやっぱりやっぱり大好き
Regardless of what I say, I really, after all, after all, love you
這い寄りましたじゃ、また来週！
We've crawled here, so see you next week!
SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！SAN値！ピンチ！
SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch! SAN value! Pinch!
にゃっ！にゃっ！
Nya! Nya!
恋は渾沌の隷也
Love is a slave to chaos
現れし私はだあれ？
Who am I that has appeared?
恋は渾沌の隷也
Love is a slave to chaos
選ばれし君の神ですよ
I am your chosen god
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The strange future Nyarlathotep
困らせて幸せになれ
Trouble them and become happy
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The strange future Nyarlathotep
愛すべき君の神ですよ
I am your lovable god
ラブをクラフト戦いながらね
While fighting for love-crafting
とか何とか言っても本当はこんなにこんなに大好き
Regardless of what I say, I really love you this much, this much
這い寄りますか？ せーの、うねり！
Shall we crawl? One, two, surge!
チェックのキャミソールを着て
Wearing a checkered camisole
今夜…ねえ！ 遊びにゆくわ
Tonight... hey! I'm going out to play
スウィートな服は宝物
Sweet clothes are treasures
君はすこし 恥ずかしそうね
You look a little bit shy
ハートのネイルのピンクは...
The pink of my heart-shaped nails...
ホントはちょっと、大胆よ
Is actually a little bit bold
12時すぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella after midnight
もっと 夢見せて
Show me more dreams
もっと そばに来て
Come closer to me
tonight 二人きり
Tonight, just the two of us
Let's Party!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby
世界一可愛い子に
To be the cutest girl in the world
生まれたかった
Is what I wished for
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 言われても
No matter how many times you tell me
まだ不安なの
I'm still insecure
あ・い・し・て・る？
Do you love me?
カートにあふれてしまうほど
So much it overflows the cart
今日は...ねぇ！お買い物の日
Today is... hey! shopping day
スウィートな 帽子と手袋
A sweet hat and gloves
お洒落すると キラキラするの
When I dress up, I sparkle
大きなハートが欲しい
I want a big heart
ホントはちょっと弱虫よ
Actually, I'm a bit of a coward
シープのブーツ脱ぎ捨てて
Kicking off my sheepskin boots
もっと 愛される
I want to be loved more
SweetGirl 女の子
SweetGirl, a girl
ねぇ 目指したい
Hey, I want to aim for it
from My Heart
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby
世界一可愛いって
That I'm the cutest in the world
今日も言ってね
Tell me again today
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 生まれても
No matter how many times I'm born
君に会いたい
I want to meet you
本当よ
It's true
助手くん、盛り上がってるー！？
Assistants, are you excited!?
行くよー！
Here we go!
せーの！
Ready, set!
イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
まだまだ声出せるんじゃないの！？
You can shout louder than that, can't you!?
もっともっと盛り上がってこー！
Let's get even more hyped!
イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
やればできるじゃーん！
See, you can do it!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ハートのネイルのピンクは...
The pink of my heart-shaped nails...
ホントはもっと、大胆よ
Is actually even bolder
12時すぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella after midnight
もっと 夢見せて
Show me more dreams
もっと そばに来て
Come closer to me
tonight 大事よ
Tonight is important
Let's Party!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって
That I'm the cutest in the world
今日も言ってね
Tell me again today
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 生まれても
No matter how many times I'm born
君に会いたい
I want to meet you
約束よ
It's a promise
世界でいちばんおひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い 心得てよね
Know how to treat me like that, okay?
ワールドイズマイン
作詞・作曲：ryo
World is Mine
Lyrics & Composition: ryo
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
One: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual
その二 ちゃんと靴までみること いいね？
Two: Make sure to look down to my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Three: Reply to every word of mine with three sentences
わかったら右手がお留守なのになんとかして！
If you understand, my right hand is empty, so do something about it!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
キミに心から思って欲しいの 可愛いって
I want you to think it from your heart: that I'm cute
可愛いって
That I'm cute
世界でいちばんおひめさま
The number one princess in the world
世界で一番おひめさま
気がついて　ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question
わたしを　だれだと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか
I'm just...
あまいものが食べたい！
...starting to want something sweet!
いますぐによ
Right now!
Oh!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must mean 'cute'
文句は許しませんの
I won't tolerate any complaints
あのね、わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？
Listen, are you paying attention to me?
ちょっと……
Wait...
あ、それとね
Ah, and another thing
白いお馬さん　決まってるでしょ？
You've decided on the white horse, right?
迎えに来て
Come and pick me up
わかったらかしずいて手を取って
If you understand, kneel and take my hand
「おひめさま」って
And say, "Princess"
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
でもね　少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま
You're my one and only prince in the world
気がついて　ほらほら
Notice me, look, look
おててが空いてます
My hand is empty
無口で　無愛想なおうじさま
A quiet and unsociable prince
もうどうして！
Oh, why?!
気がついてよ早く
Notice me already!
Oh!
ぜったい
You absolutely...
君はわかってない！
...don't understand!
わかってないわ……
You don't understand...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
A strawberry shortcake
こだわりたまごの　とろけるプリン
And melting pudding made with special eggs
みんな　みんな　我慢します……
I'll hold back on all of them...
わがままな子だと思わないで
So don't think I'm a selfish girl
わたしだってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try
あとで後悔するわよ
You'll regret it later
当然です！だってわたしは
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
...the number one princess in the world
ちゃんと見ててよね
Keep your eyes on me
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Or I might go somewhere else
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly, I was held tight
急にそんな！　えっ？
So suddenly! Wait, what?
「轢かれる　危ないよ」
"You'll get run over, it's dangerous"
そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
You said that and looked away
……こっちのが危ないわよ
...This side is the dangerous one
Ah!
はぁ。一瞬SAN値ピンチになりつつも、思わずコールをしてしまった。
Haa. Even though my Sanity Points were in a pinch for a moment, I ended up calling out without thinking.
こんこよアイランドに体がなじんできたようだな。
It seems my body has grown accustomed to Konkoyo Island.
……と、ここは？　アニマルパーク？
Wait, where is this? Animal Park?
観光名所かな？　遊んでいこう。
Is it a tourist spot? I'll go check it out.
もうキミのココロ　ジャックしちゃえ
I'm going to hijack your heart now
わおーん！
Wao-n!
アニマルパークへようこそ！
Welcome to Animal Park!
まずは一緒にわおーんしようね
First, let's howl together!
絶対無理って思っちゃうし
I end up thinking it's absolutely impossible
だって　だって　不安になるし
Because, because, I get anxious
全然嘘つけないし
I can't tell a lie at all
だって　だって　バカ正直だし
Because, because, I'm foolishly honest
目指すキラキラ　きっとボク次第だ
The sparkle I aim for surely depends on me
ビター？　ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Bitter? I'm not going to say I give up
じっとしてらんないし
I can't stay still
だって　だって　動いちゃう脚
Because, because, my legs keep moving
1, 1 ステップ　ちょっとずつ進めば
Step by step, if I move forward a little at a time
夢の式　解けちゃうの
I'll solve the equation of dreams
成りたい僕を　君が好きな僕を
The person I want to be, the person you like
ちゃんと余りなく見せたいな
I want to show you all of me
あっちゃちゃ　びっくりするほどできないじゃん
Oops, I can't do it as well as I'd like
間違って悩んだりバカじゃん
Making mistakes and worrying is silly
けどキミに見つけて欲しくて
But I want you to find me
ボクは君を迎えに行くんだ　出会えたならハッピー
I'm coming to get you, I'm happy we met
わーお　わーおだ　叫んじゃえ
Wao, wao! Let's shout it out!
泣いて　喚いて　愛して　尻尾振って
Crying, shouting, loving, wagging my tail
わーお　わーおだ　叫んじゃえ
Wao, wao! Let's shout it out!
ダメな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember the imperfect me
もうキミのココロ　ジャックしちゃえ
I'm going to hijack your heart now
もうどうしようとか　たまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and feel down
案外いけるかも　ふわり浮かんじゃって元通り
But then I think I can do it and feel light again
べったりがやめられない　おすわりって何だっけ？
I can't stop clinging, what was 'sit' again?
ベッタリがやめられない おすわりって何だっけ？
I can't stop clinging, what was "sit" again?
うっかりが止められない また歩いて棒に当たるの
I can't stop being careless, I bump into poles while walking again
ワン・ワンス・ステップ・アップ・アップ
One, once, step, up, up
死んだふりしてるのやめて
Stop playing dead
ほいっ こっちおいで
Hey, come over here
欲しがる君とあげすぎな僕とで
Between the wanting you and the giving-too-much me
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further
じっくりするほどできないじゃん
The more I take it slow, the less I can do
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
It's all about making mistakes and worrying
けど君に見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
I'm coming to pick you up, I'll be happy if we meet
だって やっぱり一人じゃダメだけど
Because, after all, being alone is no good
集まってばかしてわおっちゃえば
If we get together, fool around, and say "Wao!"
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり！」
See, I can say "Welcome home!" anytime
僕は君に伝えたいんだ 大いなるハッピー
I want to tell you about this great happiness
わーお！
Wao!
叫んじゃえ！
Shout it out!
泣いて 鳴いて 愛して 尻尾振って
Cry out, bark, love, wag your tail
わーお！
Wao!
叫んじゃえ！
Shout it out!
だめな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember the useless me
目指すキラキラもきっと僕次第だ！
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me!
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I won't say things like "I give up"
加速メラメラでぶっちぎる次第です
I'm going to break through with burning acceleration
はぐれずに希望へ大爆走
Racing towards hope without getting lost
きみの心チクっとしちゃって
Making your heart sting a little
いいじゃん ハッピーじゃん
It's fine, isn't it happy?
エビバディ解体 思い出に消しゴム！？ あれっ。
Everybody dismantling, an eraser for memories!? Huh.
ハイになる？ハイになる？「はい」とは言えなーい！！！
Getting high? Getting high? I can't say "yes"!!!
おかしい世界 お菓子は消えちゃう！？ どうしよ。
Strange world, sweets disappear!? What should I do.
“どうして！？”も“あーして！！”も君らしくないね？
"Why!?" and "Do that!!" are so not like you, right?
ソンな時代でいいよ
Such times are fine
僕らまだ“ワンダー”信じてる、
We still believe in "wonder",
のの No? know!
No, no, No? know!
おとなたちの鋭利な目盛り(メモリ)
The sharp scales (Memory) of adults
悩まされすぎちゃって 寄り目になっちゃいそーね！！
Getting too worried, I might end up cross-eyed!!
“どうして！？”“あーして！！”全部大好き！がいいじゃん！！
"Why!?" "Do that!!" "I love it all!" is good, isn't it!!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの魂胆で
With the intention of making everyone, everyone laugh
宿敵逆境モンスター呼んじゃったっていいじゃん！？
It's fine to call out archenemies and adversity monsters, isn't it!?
スットンキョウでサイキョウなセカイを！
To a crazy and strongest world!
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん！！
Unsavable difficulties are fine too!!
みんなみんな救っちゃお！のポーズで
With the "Let's save everyone, everyone!" pose
ちょっとやそっとじゃ崩れない笑顔どうじゃん！
How about a smile that doesn't crumble easily!
100回オテでも不思議は踊りださない
Even after 100 times of "paw", the mystery won't dance
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー
One-one, on the same page, three-four
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
デモデモセンセイ トワワササンザン 答は数多！ うー！
But, but Teacher, gossip is terrible, answers are numerous! Uwa!
ハイになる？ハイになる？0点じゃないなら、OK！
Getting high? Getting high? If it's not 0 points, then OK!
マルバツ全部一切合切ウチューしよう！
Let's make all the circles and crosses everything "cosmic"!
正解も不正解も大切なメモリー
Correct and incorrect answers are both precious memories
つまずく日もあるよ
There are days we stumble
君はまだ“ワンダー”否定してる、
You still deny the "wonder",
のの No? know!
No, no, No? know!
崩す前に、聞いてよ待って！
Before it crumbles, listen, wait!
トンがりすぎちゃう世界に ツッコんで、トンで、もう一回！？
To the too-sharp world, crack a joke, fly, and one more time!?
成功失敗も「全部大好き！」でいいじゃん！！
Success and failure, "I love it all!" is fine!!
みんなみんなウチューしよう？の魂胆で
With the intention of making everyone, everyone "cosmic"?
だってだって君ももっと笑えたじゃん！？
Because, because you could laugh more too, right!?
スットンキョウでサイキョウな僕らは！
We, the crazy and strongest ones!
まだまだ消さないで！？未来はここからじゃん！！
Don't erase it yet!? The future starts from here!!
みんなみんな一緒しよ！のポーズで
With the "Let's all be together!" pose
ちょっとやそっとじゃ崩れない笑顔と
With a smile that doesn't crumble easily
100回トンだらトンデモお菓子いセカイ
After 100 jumps, a crazy, sweet world
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー
One-one, on the same page, three-four
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでもう一回
Joke, fly, boom, and one more time even if you're cold
3. 2. 1. ミステイク
3. 2. 1. Mistake
3. 2. 1. わあ！
3. 2. 1. Waa!
セカイ解体10秒前！？ 待って待って待って
World dismantling in 10 seconds!? Wait, wait, wait
まだまだ一緒しよ？の魂胆です
The intention is to still be together?
101回目のソンなメモリー(記憶)拝借
Borrowing that 101st memory
“ハッピーも失敗も消さないから！！”
“Because I won't erase the happiness or the failures!!”
セカイ ウチュー 未来 超大好きでギューじゃん！！
World, Cosmos, Future, I love it all so much, it's a tight squeeze!!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの正解は
The answer to making everyone, everyone laugh is
宿敵逆境モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん！
It's fine to call out archenemies and adversity monsters!
スットンキョウでサイキョウ、お菓子いだろ？
Crazy and strongest, it's sweet, right?
旋回満開もう一回大好きでギューじゃん！
Rotating, in full bloom, one more time, I love it all, a tight squeeze!
みんなみんなくすぐっちゃえ！のポーズで
With the "Let's tickle everyone, everyone!" pose
ぜったいぜったい消せない笑顔どうじゃん！
How about a smile that definitely, definitely can't be erased!
∞(むげん)回オテでも不思議は取り壊せない
Even after infinite "paws", the mystery can't be demolished
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー
One-one, on the same page, three-four
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
ワンワンでツーカーで
One-one, on the same page,
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
ワンワンでツーカーで
One-one, on the same page,
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでもう一回
Joke, fly, boom, and one more time even if you're cold
わんわん！ショウタイム！わぁ〜楽しかったなぁ〜
Wan-wan! Showtime! Wow~ that was fun~
ケモ耳最高ー！
Beast ears are the best!
…こほん。こんこよアイランド、いいところじゃないか。
...Ahem. Konkoyo Island is a nice place, isn't it.
ってあれ？あのこ、アニマルパークにいた子じゃ？
Wait, huh? That girl, isn't she the one who was at the Animal Park?
追ってみよう
Let's follow her.
オリジナルじゃなくてもいい
It doesn't have to be original.
僕を見てくれますか？
Will you look at me?
ファジーネーブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I could go anywhere
甘い苦い切ない想いを
The sweet, bitter, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
真面目すぎるその姿が好き
I like how you're so serious
私には似合わない
It doesn't suit me
それでも横にいられたらと
Even so, I wish I could be by your side
そう思う、いやそうやって思ってる
That's what I think, no, that's what I'm thinking
もう何回も呼んでいる　君の名前も
I've called your name so many times already
もう何回も夢に見た　2人の世界も
The world of just us two that I've seen in my dreams so many times
もう何回も何回も諦めようとして
Trying to give up so many, many times
戻って君に酔ってしまう
I come back and get drunk on you
私になってゆく
Becoming me
ファジーネーブルの匂いで
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I could go anywhere
許すたび心まで　オレンジ色に染まる
Every time I forgive you, even my heart turns orange
ファジーネーブルの匂いで
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel
君とどこか飛んでいけそう
I feel like I could fly somewhere with you
甘い甘い切ない想いを
The sweet, sweet, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
悲しすぎるその結末はもう
That ending that's just too sad
私言わなくても分かってるの
I already know without you saying a word
それでも横にいたいなんて
Even so, wishing to be by your side
そんなこと思えないよ
I can't even think such a thing
オレンジに染まった　5%の想いは
The 5% of feelings dyed in orange
私の思い出に溶けてしまう
Dissolve into my memories
消えてしまう前に
Before they disappear
ファジーネーブルの匂いで
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I could go anywhere
許すたび心まで　オレンジ色に染まる
Every time I forgive you, even my heart turns orange
ファジーネーブルの匂いで
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel
君とどこか飛んでいけそう
I feel like I could fly somewhere with you
甘い甘い切ない想いを
The sweet, sweet, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
はい！ということで、AIこよりが初めて歌にチャレンジしましたー！
Yes! And with that, AI Koyori has taken on her first singing challenge!
AIこより、どうだった？
AI Koyori, how was it?
緊張したけれど、こよりちゃんと一緒に歌えて嬉しかったです。
I was nervous, but I was happy to be able to sing with Koyori-chan.
うんうん！みんなも、こんな特別ゲストがいるなんて思わなかったんじゃない？
Yeah, yeah! I bet everyone didn't expect such a special guest, right?
僕が特別ゲストだなんて、とんでもない。
Me, a special guest? Not at all.
え？
Eh?
もっとすごい方が、こんこよアイランドに迷い込んでるみたいですよ。
It seems someone even more amazing has wandered into Konkoyo Island.
な、なんだってー！？
W-What did you say!?
あ、あの方はー！
Th-That person is...!
ポケモン！ゲットだぜ！
Pokémon! Get daze!
たとえ火の中 水の中 草の中 森の中
Even in fire, in water, in grass, in forests
土の中 雲の中 あのコのスカートの中
In the dirt, in the clouds, in that girl's skirt
なかなか なかなか なかなか なかなか 大変だけど
It's quite, quite, quite, quite tough, but
かならずGETだぜ！
I'll definitely get 'em!
ポケモンGETだぜ！
Pokémon get daze!
ポケモンGETだぜ!
I'll get Pokémon!
マサラタウンに さよならバイバイ
Goodbye to Pallet Town, bye-bye
オレはこいつと 旅に出る
I'm heading out on a journey with this guy
(ぴかちゅう!)
(Pikachu!)
きたえたワザで 勝ちまくり
Winning again and again with trained moves
仲間をふやして 次の町へ
Making more friends and moving to the next town
いつもいつでも うまくゆくなんて
That things will always go smoothly
保証はどこにも ないけど
There's no guarantee anywhere
(そりゃそうじゃ!)
(That's for sure!)
いつでもいつも ホンキで生きてる
Always, at any time, living in earnest
こいつたちがいる
These guys are here
(ピカピカ ぴかぴか ぴかちゅうー!)
(Pika-pika, pika-pika, Pikachu!)
たとえ火の中 水の中 草の中 森の中
Even if it's in fire, in water, in grass, in forests
土の中 雲の中 あの子のスカートの中
In the earth, in the clouds, under that girl's skirt
(きゃー!)
(Kyaa!)
なかなか なかなか なかなか なかなか 大変だけど
It's quite, quite, quite, quite a challenge but
かならずGETだぜ!
I'll definitely get 'em!
ポケモンGETだぜ!
I'll get Pokémon!
たたかいつかれて おやすみグッナイ
Tired out from battling, sleep tight, good night
まぶたを閉じれば よみがえる
If you close your eyelids, they come back to life
(ぴかちゅう?)
(Pikachu?)
ほのおが燃えて かぜが舞い
Flames burning, wind dancing
鳴き声とどろく あのバトルが
Cries echoing from that battle
きのうの敵は きょうの友って
They say yesterday's enemy is today's friend
古いコトバが あるけれど
As the old saying goes
(古めとはなんじゃーっ!)
(What do you mean, old?!)
きょうの友は あしたも友だち
Today's friend will be a friend tomorrow too
そうさ 永遠に
That's right, forever
(そうさ 永遠に)
(That's right, forever)
(ピカピカ ぴかぴか ぴかちゅうー!)
(Pika-pika, pika-pika, Pikachu!)
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに
Ah, to be the long-admired Pokémon Master
なりたいな ならなくちゃ
I want to be, I have to be
ゼッタイなってやるーッ!
I'll definitely become one!
ユメはいつか ホントになるって
That dreams will one day come true
だれかが歌って いたけれど
Someone was singing it, but
つぼみがいつか 花ひらくように
Like a bud blooming one day
ユメは かなうもの
Dreams are meant to come true
いつもいつでも うまくゆくなんて
That things will always go smoothly
保証はどこにも ないけど
There's no guarantee anywhere
(そりゃそうじゃ!)
(That's for sure!)
いつでもいつも ホンキで生きてる
Always, at any time, living in earnest
こいつたちがいる
These guys are here
(ピカピカ ぴかぴか ぴかちゅうー!)
(Pika-pika, pika-pika, Pikachu!)
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに
Ah, to be the long-admired Pokémon Master
なりたいな ならなくちゃ
I want to be, I have to be
ゼッタイなってやるーッ!
I'll definitely become one!
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに
Ah, to be the long-admired Pokémon Master
なりたいな ならなくちゃ
I want to be, I have to be
ゼッタイなってやるーッ!
I'll definitely become one!
はい! ということで、なんと「こんこよアイランド」に
Alright! And so, believe it or not, the one who
紛れ込んだのは、松本梨香さんでしたー!
wandered into 'Konkoyo Island' was Rica Matsumoto!
どうも! さっそくエントリー、松本梨香です!
Hello! Joining the entry right away, I'm Rica Matsumoto!
イェーイ! 梨香ねぇー!
Yay! Rica-nee!
梨香ねぇー!
Rica-nee!
梨香ねぇとはですね、えー以前ホロライブの
Regarding Rica-nee, well, previously on the
ファンクラブの番組「ホロテス」でご一緒させていただきまして。
Hololive fan club program 'HoloTest', we were together.
久しぶりだね!
It's been a while!
お久しぶりですよー!
It certainly has been!
元気?
How've you been?
元気です! あけましておめでとうございます!
I'm great! Happy New Year!
ちょっと痩せた?
Did you lose a little weight?
えっ、あ、わかります?
Eh, oh, you can tell?
ちょっとあのボン・キュッ・ボンに磨きがかかったんですけど。
I've been working on my 'bom-kyu-bom' (hourglass) figure.
え、あの、あともう一つ、ちょっとアピールしたいことがあって。
And, um, there's one more thing I want to mention.
ぜーぜー言ってるけど大丈夫?
You're panting, are you okay?
あ、大丈夫です。ちょっと緊張、整えていいよ。
Ah, I'm fine. A bit nervous, you can take a moment.
息いいよ、整えていいよ。あ、ありがとう。
Catch your breath, it's okay. Ah, thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい。うんうん、何々?
Okay. Yeah yeah, what is it?
実は、あの、こより今日で一つ大人になったんです。
Actually, um, Koyori became one year older today.
え、どういうこと? 大人の階段登る...って、何?
Eh, what do you mean? Climbing the stairs to adulthood... what?
あ、登ったんですよ。あの、要するにバースデーということで。え、ハッピーバースデー?
Ah, I climbed them. Um, basically, it's my birthday. Oh, Happy Birthday?
はい!
Yes!
Happy Birthday to you...
Happy Birthday dear Koyori-...
ちょっとネイティブ出ちゃいました。Happy Birthday to you!
My native accent came out a bit. Happy Birthday to you!
嬉しいー! 梨香ねぇありがとうございます!
I'm so happy! Thank you so much, Rica-nee!
え、ちょっと待って。
Wait, hold on a second.
ハッピーバースデー迎えたってことで、えーと、抱負。
So, since it's your birthday... your resolution?
抱負？抱負？
Resolution? Resolution?
急に？
Suddenly?
あ、でも、今一緒に歌わせていただいて、
Ah, well, getting to sing together just now...
ものすごい、もうやっぱ声量にビクンビクンさせられまして。
your vocal volume really blew me away!
そうそう、あの小さいときからね、あの声は本当にデカいんだ。
Exactly. My voice has been really loud since I was little.
いや、もう本当にすごい。
No, it's really amazing.
それを感じて、より、歌、今年頑張ろうっていうのが、
Feeling that, it made me think I'll work even harder on my singing this year,
元々抱負だったんですけど、より思いました。
which was my resolution, but now I feel it even more.
そうだね。うん。そうそう。
That's good. Yeah, exactly.
まあ、楽しく歌えばいいんですよ、歌なんて。
Well, you just have to sing happily, after all.
あ、でも、めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです。もうほんとに。
Ah, but it was so much fun! Truly.
だってほら、音楽ってやっぱり音を楽しむじゃんか。
Because look, 'music' is written as 'enjoying sound,' right?
だからその楽しむっていうのが一番のエネルギーになりますからね。
So, that enjoyment becomes the greatest energy.
いや、でも本当に一緒に歌わせていただいて、めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです。ありがとうございました！
No, but really, singing with you was so much fun. Thank you so much!
よかったです。私もです。ありがとう。
I'm glad. Me too. Thank you.
いや、まさかあの子供の頃から聴いて歌っていた、
I never thought the day would come when I'd sing together
あの曲を一緒に歌わせていただける日が来るなんて... ありがとうございます！
the song I've been listening to and singing since I was a kid... Thank you!
すみません、恐縮しすぎかもしれませんが。
I'm sorry, I might be being too humble, but...
よくね、みんな小さい頃からって言うのよ。
People often say 'since I was little.'
それちょっとね、どのぐらい？っていうふうに思っちゃって。
I end up thinking, 'Exactly how long ago was that?'
はい。でもありがたいですね。本当にありがたいです。本当にありがとうございます。
Yes. But I'm grateful. Truly grateful. Thank you very much.
ということで、ここ、こよラボというこよりのラボなんですけど、仮想世界、どうですか？
So, this is 'Koyo-Lab,' Koyori's laboratory. What do you think of the virtual world?
そうね。え、すごい、素敵！
I see. Wow, it's wonderful!
やったー！
Yay!
でもなんかずっと、なんか色んなのが動いてて落ち着かないんだけど。
But, you know, things are moving around all the time, so it's a bit restless.
すみません、ちょっと。
Sorry about that.
あのね、コンベアに...
Um, on the conveyor belt...
コンベアに乗ってみたい、そのコンベアに。
I want to try riding the conveyor belt. That one.
え、ええ！？乗ってくれるんですか？
Wh-What!? You'll ride it?
乗って、帰っていいかな？
Can I ride it and go home?
あれに乗ったら、もれなく、こよりの助手君になるっていう、おまけ付きなんですけど。
If you ride that, you automatically become one of Koyori's assistants as a bonus.
そうなんだ。
Is that so?
じゃあ、梨香ねぇ、今日からこよりの助手君ということで。
So, Rica-nee, from today on, you're Koyori's assistant.
いや、じゃあいいや。
In that case, never mind.
えぇーっ！？助手にならなくていいから乗ってってください、後で！
Eeeh!? You don't have to be an assistant, so please ride it later!
ということで、こんこよアイランドも、これからちょっと、もうちょっと楽しんでいただければと思います。ありがとうございました！
Anyway, I hope you continue to enjoy Kon-Koyo Island a little longer. Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ということで、松本梨香さんでした！ありがとうございました！
And so, that was Matsumoto Rica-san! Thank you so much!
じゃあ、乗って帰ろうかな。
Well, I guess I'll ride this home.
あ、乗ってる！
Ah, she's riding it!
わ～、びっくりなゲストだったな～！楽しかった～
Wow, what a surprising guest that was! It was so much fun!
！？な、なんだ！？急に目の前が真っ暗に！
!? Wh-What is this!? Suddenly, everything's gone dark!
そこに跪け！
Kneel before me!
吐いて捨てるような現実は
A reality like something spat out and discarded...
一刀両断 叩き切る
I'll cut it down with a single stroke.
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし 子等よ
O children lost in endless reincarnation...
漆黒の翼で 誘おう
Allow me to invite you with jet-black wings.
我ら、エデンの星を統べる者
We are the rulers of the Star of Eden,
秘密結社holoXでござる！
The Secret Society holoX!
会いたかったよ
I wanted to see you.
会いたかったわ
会いたかった
I wanted to see you.
会いたかったです
やっと 会えました
Finally, we've met.
大好きって気持ちは もっともっと増えてく
The feeling of 'I love you' keeps growing more and more.
溢れて止まらない 君にちゃんと届くように
Overflowing and unstoppable, so it properly reaches you.
こんこよアイランド、楽しんでるー？
Are you enjoying Kon-Koyo Island?
最後はライブステージを楽しんでいってね！
Enjoy the live stage until the very end!
イェーイ！
Yay!
1、2、3、4、5！
1, 2, 3, 4, 5!
止まったままの 5人 すれ違う気持ち
The five who stayed still, feelings passing each other by.
君のその心が 溶かしてく
Your heart will melt them away.
特別な形は 消えない奇跡描く
This special form draws an unfading miracle.
これからも ずっとずっと 変わらないで
From now on, forever and ever, don't ever change.
大好きって気持ちは もっともっと増えてく
The feeling of 'I love you' keeps growing more and more.
大切なんだ全部 ひとつひとつ抱きしめて
Everything is precious; I'll embrace each and every part.
今の愛だってほら 5等分にしていこう
Look, even this current love—let's divide it into five.
溢れて止まらない 君にちゃんと届くように
Overflowing and unstoppable, so it properly reaches you.
分かり合っても どれも 譲れない気持ち
Even if we understand each other, none of these feelings can be yielded.
何が大切かって 気づいてく
We'll come to realize what's truly important.
切り替わった形は 永遠の奇跡紡ぐ
The changed form spins an eternal miracle.
真っ直ぐな 君に惹かれていく
I'm being drawn to your honest self.
大好きって言えたら もっともっと高鳴る
If I can say 'I love you,' my heart will pound even more.
会いたいんだ今すぐ 逸る気持ち駆け出して
I want to see you right now; my impatient heart starts racing.
ちょっと待って止まらない ずっとドキドキしてる
Wait a moment, it won't stop; my heart has been throbbing all along.
一瞬も忘れない あの日いつも夢に見る
I won't forget for a single second; I always dream of that day.
沢山の思い出が
So many memories
積み重なって
piling up
それぞれに歩き出した未来でも
even in the future where we've each started walking our own paths
みんな同じ思いが
everyone's feelings are the same
変わらない続いていくよ
and will continue without changing
大好きって気持ちは
The feeling of "I love you"
絶対消したくない
I never want it to disappear
だって全部私でしょ
Because that's all part of who I am, right?
大好きって気持ちはもっともっと増えていく
The feeling of "I love you" will grow more and more
大切なんだ全部一つ一つ抱きしめて
It's all precious, I'll embrace every single bit
喜怒哀楽だってほら全部味にして行こう
Look, let's turn even all our emotions into flavor
溢れて止まらない君にちゃんと届くように
Overflowing and unstoppable, so that it reaches you properly
さあ！夢を叶えるのはみんなの勇気
Come on! It's everyone's courage that makes dreams come true
負けない心で明日へ駆けていこう
With an undying heart, let's run toward tomorrow
強い強い願い事が
Strong, powerful wishes
僕たちを導いてくれた
guided us
次は絶対譲れないよ
Next time, I won't back down
残された時間を握りしめて
clutching the remaining time
ただの思い出それだけじゃ嫌だよ
I don't want it to be just a mere memory
精一杯力の限り走るんだ
I'll run with all my might as much as I can
(Chance for me! Chance for you!)
さあ！夢を抱きしめたら
Come on! Once you embrace your dreams
上を向いて
look up
君の世界が大きく変わるよ
Your world will change significantly
さあ！夢を叶えるのはみんなの勇気
Come on! It's everyone's courage that makes dreams come true
負けない心で明日へ駆けていこう
With an undying heart, let's run toward tomorrow
熱い熱い期待の中で
Amidst hot, burning expectations
僕たちは喜びを歌おう
let's sing of joy
同じ思い感じてみてよ
Try feeling the same way
限られた時間を楽しもうよ
let's enjoy the limited time
もう止められない
You can't stop it now
情熱の価値だね
it's the value of passion
悔やむより走り続けよう
Let's keep running rather than regretting
ふいに見た空こんなにも青いよ
The sky I suddenly looked at is so blue
大丈夫諦めないで走るんだ
It's okay, don't give up, keep running
(Dance with me! Dance with you!)
そうあの日夢見たのは
Yes, what we dreamed of that day
みんなの笑顔
was everyone's smiles
君の笑顔さ宝物だよ
Your smile is a treasure
笑ってよ
so please smile
そうあの日同じ夢を描いたんだ
Yes, on that day, we painted the same dream
輝く瞳は明日を信じてた
Sparkling eyes believed in tomorrow
最後まで駆け抜けるよ
I'll run through until the very end
さあ！夢を抱きしめたら
Come on! Once you embrace your dreams
上を向いて
look up
君の世界が大きく変わるよ
Your world will change significantly
さあ！夢を叶えるのは
Come on! It's everyone's courage that
みんなの勇気
makes dreams come true
負けない心で
With an undying heart
明日へ駆けていこう
let's run toward tomorrow
そうあの日夢見たのは
Yes, what we dreamed of that day
みんなの笑顔
was everyone's smiles
さあ、笑ってよ
Come on, let's smile
そう、あの日と同じ夢を描いたんだ
Yes, we shared the same dream as that day
輝く瞳は明日を信じてた
Our shining eyes believed in tomorrow
負けない心で明日を信じてた
With a heart that wouldn't give up, we believed in tomorrow
今ここで出会えた奇跡
The miracle of meeting here now
忘れないで僕たちの季節
Don't forget our season together
そんな君は運が良い！
Then you're in luck!
実は出来立てほやほやのオリジナル曲があるんだよ！
Actually, I have a brand-new original song for you!
新オリジナル曲、New Journey。聴いてね！
My new original song, "New Journey." Please listen!
素敵だね ひとりじゃない 新しい旅
It's wonderful, you're not alone on a new journey
New Journey
何を求められてるの？
What are you looking for?
矛盾だらけの世界で
In a world full of contradictions
何を信じればいいのか 彷徨い歩いてた
Wandering around, not knowing what to believe in
どんな夢でもいいから
No matter what the dream is
長い道のりを進もう
Let's move forward on this long road
困難が待ち受けていても 仲間と乗り越えよう
Even if hardships await, let's overcome them with our friends
ひとりで迷い続けていた日々を
The days when I was lost and wandering alone
震えないで力強く 止めてみせるよ
Don't tremble; I'll stop it with all my strength
初めて正義を共に掲げれば
If we hold up justice together for the first time
思い通りの光が 真っ直ぐに飛び出していく
The light we imagine will fly straight ahead
羽ばたいて 忘れないでね この眩しさを
Spread your wings and don't forget this radiance
希望に満ちた輝き 追いかけて
Chasing after the brilliance filled with hope
あり得ない景色に 辿り着きましょう
Let's reach that impossible scenery together
答え探しはいつでも
Searching for answers, always
僕らを困らせるけど
It tends to trouble us, but
戸惑いなんていらない 今日から歩き出そう
No need for hesitation; let's start walking from today
汚れた空は綺麗に
The polluted sky will clear up beautifully
冷たい雨は消え去る
The cold rain will fade away
切ない夜が明ければ 風向き変わりだす
Once the painful night ends, the wind will start to change
大きな雲を動かし立ち上がり
Move the giant clouds and stand tall
両手広げ走り出そう 扉を開けて
Spread your arms, start running, and open the door
壊れた夢は拾い集めて
Gather up the broken dreams
並べ替えれば良いから
It's fine as long as you rearrange them
完璧を求めなくても
You don't have to seek perfection
追い詰められて悲しくなっても
Even if you're cornered and feel sad
諦めないで続けよう
Don't give up; let's keep going
白い月 愛しい星たちも 僕らを照らす
The white moon and the beloved stars will also shine upon us
初めて正義を共に掲げれば
If we hold up justice together for the first time
思い通りの光が
The light we imagine
真っ直ぐに飛び出していく
Will fly straight ahead
羽ばたいて 忘れないでね この眩しさを
Spread your wings and don't forget this radiance
希望に満ちた輝き 追いかけて
Chasing after the brilliance filled with hope
あり得ない景色に
Toward that impossible scenery
辿り着きましょう
Let's reach it together
みんなー！今日はこんこよアイランドに
Everyone! Thank you for coming to
遊びに来てくれて、ありがとう！
Konkoyo Island today!
観光の後は、お土産をゲットだ！
After sightseeing, it's time to get some souvenirs!
ということで、大切なお知らせです！
And with that, I have some important announcements!
まず、今歌った新しいオリジナル曲、
First, the new original song I just performed,
New Journeyはこの後24時から販売開始！
'New Journey', will be available starting at midnight tonight!
水樹奈々さんの曲を始め、たくさんの方に愛される
It was created by Toshiro Yabuki and Tsutomu Ohira,
矢吹俊郎さん、大平勉さんに作っていただいた、
who have worked on many famous anime songs,
アニメ博衣こよりのオープニングテーマみたいな
including those for Nana Mizuki. It's a cool song
カッコいい曲です！ゲットしてヘビロテしてね！
like an anime opening theme! Please play it on repeat!
そして、この後すぐ！
And right after this!
こよが作詞したオリジナル曲、Tear-Gazerの
The animated MV for 'Tear-Gazer', an original song
アニメーションMVがプレミア公開されます！
I wrote the lyrics for, will have its premiere!
初めてのアニメーションMV、絶対見てね！
It's my first animated MV, so please be sure to watch it!
続いて、こんこよアイランドの観光お土産、
Next, it's time for the long-awaited introduction of
お待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！
Konkoyo Island souvenirs - the merchandise!
今回は、海のレジャーセット！
This time, it's a sea leisure set!
「海の想い出」B2タペストリー！
The 'Sea Memories' B2 Tapestry!
アイランドでの海の思い出を飾ろう！
Decorate your room with memories of the island's sea!
ももこママ描き下ろしの水着タペストリー！
A swimsuit tapestry illustrated by Momoko-mama!
そして、タペストリーを見ながら聞くのにぴったり、
And, perfect for listening to while looking at the
「いっしょに海で大はしゃぎ」ボイスも発売するよ！
tapestry, a situation voice will also be on sale!
続いて、海といえばキンキンに冷えた飲み物だよね。
Next, when you think of the sea, you think of
こよとお揃い！タンブラー。
ice-cold drinks, right? The matching tumbler!
思い出を眺めながら美味しい飲み物を飲んでね。
Enjoy a delicious drink while reflecting on memories.
そして、出かけるときもいつもいっしょ、
And, to be with you whenever you go out,
使いやすすぎるショルダーバッグ！
the super easy-to-use Shoulder Bag!
チャームや裏地もめっちゃ良いから、要チェックだ！
The charm and lining are also really great, check it out!
そして、バッグにつけてお出かけしてね、
And, please take this with you on your bag,
こよのぬいぐるみキーホルダー パーカー水着衣装ver.！
the plush keyholder of Koyo in her swimsuit parka!
フードの脱ぎ着ができる上に、
You can put the hood on or take it off,
中にはちゃんと水着を着てるんだよ！
and I'm even wearing a swimsuit underneath!
の、覗き込むなんてエッチ！
Wh-what, peeking is so lewd!
気になる全部セットには、
The full set, which I know you're curious about,
去年大好評だった、こよが助手くんの誕生日を
includes the popular ASMR voice where I celebrate
お祝いするASMRボイスの、2024年海バージョンがつくよ！
Joshu-kun's birthday, the 2024 Sea Version!
さらに、直筆サインと箔押しメッセージ入り
Furthermore, a postcard with a handwritten signature
ポストカードも！今回は全員分、直筆で書くよ！
and a foil-pressed message! I'll hand-sign every one!
戦争を終わらせに来た。
I've come to end the war.
全員に書ける機会はなかなかないと思うので、この機会にぜひ！
Since this is a rare chance, please don't miss out!
以上、こんこよアイランドのお土産、
And that's it for the Konkoyo Island souvenirs,
こよの2024誕生日記念グッズのお知らせでした！
the announcement of Koyo's 2024 birthday goods!
こんこよアイランド、なかなか楽しい島だったなぁ。
Konkoyo Island was quite a fun island.
そんなことを思いながら、君たちは目的の島、
With those thoughts in mind, you headed for your
ホロライブアイランドへ向かうのであった。
destination, Hololive Island.
- Special Thanks -
こよりの助手くん
Koyori's Assistants
土ロリスさん
Dororis-san
画面の前の皆さま
Everyone in front of the screen
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
生誕Live来てくれてありがとう♡
こんこよアイランド楽しんでもらえた？
Thanks for coming to the Birthday Live♡
Did you enjoy Kon-Koyo Island?
「大好き」と「やりたい」を詰め込んだライヴでした！！
今年も、そんな詰め詰めの1年に一緒にしていこうね！！
It was a live filled with my "favorites" and "wants"!!
Let's make this another year like that together!!
助手くん、大好きだよ♡
Assistants, I love you♡